<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Celita Summa</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-09-27</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-12-30e</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, SATURDAY, DECEMBER 30, 1905. [EIGHT PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

              <div>
                <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

              <p>Frost at Abbassieh.
              Frost was recorded at Abbassieh yesterday
              morning, the temperature being 2 Centigrade.</p>

              <p>Diphtheria.
              An outbreak of diphtheria has occurred at
              Zeitoun and the schools have been closed.</p>

              <p>The Charlotte.
              The German corvette Charlotte is leaving
              Alexandria for Italy at 2 o’clock this afternoon.</p>

              <p>Tho Mahmal.
              Ahmed Effendi Aref, of Mansourah, has been
              appointed pharmacist to the medical staff
              accompanying the Mahmal to Mecca.</p>

              <p>New Years Gifts.
              The establishment of Messrs. Walker and
              Meimarachi in Old Bourse-street, Alexandria,
              will be opened throughout to-morrow (Sunday)
              for the convenience of the public.</p>

              <p>Buried Alive.
              A native workman of 30 years was digging
              yesterday in a pit in Menascestreet, when he
              was buried under a heavy mass of earth, which
              fell upon him and asphyxiated him. His body
              was afterwards extricated.</p>

              <p>All Saints, Cairo.
              By a notice in our advertising columns we
              see that there will be midnight service and
              celebration of Holy Communion at All Saints'
              Church, Cairo, on Sunday next, beginning at
              11.15 p.m.</p>

              <p>Coal Imports.
              From the 1st of January to the 28th inst.
              1,042,768 tons of coal were imported into
              Egypt. Wales sent 572,414, Newcastle 227,879,
              Scotland 119,294, Yorkshire 78,636, and other
              places 44,560 tons. During the same period
              last year 1,050,482 tons were received.</p>

              <p>Military Tournament.
              A meeting under the presidency of Lieut.
              Col. Markham, 1st Batt. Kings’ Royal Rifle
              Corps, will be held at Headquarters, Cairo,
              at 1.30 a.m. on Monday next, to consider
              arrangements for the forthcoming Military
              Tournament.</p>

              <p>Concert at Parish-Room, Bulkeley.
              A most successful and much appreciated con-
              cert was held last night in the Parish Room,
              Bulkeley. A large and representative audience
              listened with evident delight to the songs, the
              charming composition, "The Daisy Chain," and
              the instrumental music, which, for an amateur
              performance, was of a first class order. A full
              account of this concert will appear in our next
              issue.</p>

              <p>The New Organ for St. George's.
              Mr. John Davies, who erected the new
              organ for H.B.M.’s Garrison Church of St
              George, Mustapha Pasha, is deserving of the
              highest praise tor the able way in which he has
              put up the instrument. He is remaining a few
              days in Alexandria, and will be glad to give
              any information about the organs of the Posi-
              tive Organ Company, who make small organs,
              suitable for the drawing-room, as well as large
              ones for cathedrals and churches. Mr. Davies
              is going next week to Cairo, where his address
              will be at the Hotel du Nil.</p>

              <p>Merchant Seamen's Home.
              The 'Xmas Treat given to the seamen in
              port at the Merchant Seaman's Home yesterday
              was a most brilliant affair from every point of
              view, and 300 men sat down to dinner in two
              relays. Pressure of space compels us to hold
              over our account of the entertainment. Lady
              Blomfield begs to acknowledge the following
              subscriptions and presents for the feast: Mr.
              Abdy, 10s. ; Mrs. Macaulay, £2 ; Mr. Chitty,
              £1; Mr. Ambrose Ralli, £1; Admiral Sir Massie
              Blomfield, £1; Mrs. Dickson £1; Mrs. Rees, 10s.;
              Miss Walker, 1Os.; Mrs. Harry Barker, 5s.; Miss
              Von Sommer,6s.; Mrs. Thomas Annet, 4s.; Mrs.
              Barker, 2 turkeys; Hon. Mrs. Hopkinson,cakes;
              Mrs.Harry Barker,plum pudding;Mr. Alderson,.
              2turkeys ; Mrs. Grogan, cakes; Mr. and Mis.
              Gould, tobacco ; Mrs. Morrison, cakes ; Mrs.
              Kingham, 1 turkey: Mrs. Smith, 1 roastbeef ;
              Mrs. Ward, cakes; Miss Demech, cakes ; Miss
              Lias, cakes ; Mr. Barber, 1 ham ; Mr. Mellor,
              3 tongues; Mr. Pappa, 1 ham; Mr. Caflari, 1
              ham; Khedivial Mail Company, 1 ham, 1 roast-
              beef, and 12 ’Xmas puddings; Mrs. John Ross,
              greenery ; Ports and Lights Administration,
              flags.</p></div>










              MOERIS HOTEL

              Isherwood’s Cairo Cigarettes.
              The reputation which these Cigarettes have
              gained in the past, stands unrivalled to-day,
              because it is well-known that constant care
              and Attention is devoted to supplying really
              first-class Cigarettes only.

              EDEN PALACE HOTEL

              ANGLO-AMERICAN NILE STEAMERS

              SPECIAL LATE CABLES.






              <div>
                <head>THE MOROCCO QUESTION.</head>
              <head>FRANCE APPREHENSIVE</head>
              <head>SERIOUS MILITARY PRECAUTIONS.</head>

              (Gazette's Special Service.)
              Paris, Saturday Dec. 30.
              France is taking serious military precautions
              in view of any unexpected upshot to the
              Morocco Conference. The Kaiser's specific assu-
              rances are coupled with his declaration "To
              me alone does it belong to take a decision,”
              and this is not considered reassuring.</div>

              <div><head>LIBERAL REFORM OF ARMY.</head>
              (Gazette's Special Service.)
              London, Saturday, Dec. 30;
              Mr. Haldane, the new War Minister, has
              commenced by cancelling Mr. Arnold-Foster's
              home-service battalion scheme and has suspend-
              ed the late War Minister’s Volunteer project.</div>

              <div><head>FAMINE IN JAPAN.</head>
              (Gazette's Special Service.)
              London, Saturday, Dec. 30.
              The famine in Japan is reported to be very
              serious.</div>

              <div><head>DEATH OF MR. YERKES.</head>
              (Gazette's Special Service.)
              London, Saturday, Dec. 30.
              Mr. Yerkes, the regenerator of urban rail-
              ways and one of the greatest American finan-
              ciers, has died at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel
              in New York. Death was due to complete
              physical collapse, brought on by overwork. He
              was a great connoisseur of art and had a
              superb palace of art treasures. The Press here
              is strong in its appreciation of his character.</div>

              <div><head>NEW YORK MONEY MARKET,</head>
              (Gazette's Special Service.)
              London, Saturday, Dec. 30.
              Although day-to-day money in New York
              has gone np to 195 %, this is an entirely arti-
              ficial price, as stocks rose considerably yester-
              day.</div>

              <div><head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
              <p>The Khedive attended Friday prayers at
              the Abou el Ela mosque and returned subse-
              quently to Abdeen Palace, where he granted
              some audiences.</p>

              <p>While the Khedive was passing by Boulac-
              street yesterday morning, on his way to the
              mosque, a native woman made a scene by try-
              ing to present his Highness with a petition,
              shouting that she had been unjustly treated.
              She was quieted by a policeman.</p>

              <p>On Thursday, his Highness received General
              Faradfallah Khan, late Persian Diplomatic
              Agent at Cairo in audience, and yesterday re-
              ceived the German Commissioner of the Public
              Debt, Herr von Mohl, who had the honor to
              present his elder son, Mr. Hans von Mohl,
              lieutenant in the Imperial German Navy at
              Kiel, on Christmas leave at Cairo.</p></div>

              <div><head>THE GRAND CADI.</head>
              <p>The complications in regard to the Grand
              Cadiship of Egypt appear to be increasing.
              For some unknown reason the family of the
              newly-appointed Grand Cadi suddenly left
              Alexandria for Constantinople on Wednesday,
              and their unexpected departure has given rise
              to considerable conjecture in native circles.</p>

              <p>It is considered doubtful whether the Cadi
              will return to Egypt.</p></div>

              <div><head>NEW CAIRO BOURSE.</head>
              <p>We understand that a financial group re-
              cently put forward a scheme for the construc-
              tion of a new Bourse at Cairo near the
              Hammam, on a site belonging to the Société
              Belge de l’Esbekieh, for which they had
              acquired an option, which expires on 1st
              January next. The scheme which was recently
              put forward met with great opposition on the
              part of most of the Cairo brokers, the majority
              of whom signed and approved another scheme
              to acquire a site for a new Bourse on land
              belonging to the Société Immobilière d’Egypte.</p>

              <p>We understand that there is no probability
              of any settlement being arrived at between
              the majority of the brokers and the supporters
              of the first proposal for some little time.</p></div>

              <div><head>ASILE RUDOLPH</head>
              <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.</p>

              <p>Dear Sir,— Will you kindly permit me,
              through the medium of your columns, to thank
              the generous donors of funds and gifts in kind,
              who, during the year now closing, have so
              liberally contributed to the carrying on of the
              work of the Home, and have by their kind
              help enabled me to do far more for the poor
              than I could have been accomplished without
              their assistance.</p>

              <p>Also to thank you, Mr. Editor, for allowing
              me to make use of your columns to publicly
              acknowledge the gifts.—I am, etc.,
              P. Rudolph.
              Alexandria, Dec. 30,</p></div>

              <div><head>LA DOGARESSA.</head>

              <head>M. SINADINO'S FIRST OPERA.</head>

              <head>YESTERDAY’S DRESS REHEARSAL</head>

              <p>It was yesterday our privilege to attend
              the dress rehearsal of La Dogaressa, a 3-act
              opera composed by M. N. Sinadino, with
              the book by M. V. Sinano, both such promi-
              nent members of Alexandrian society as to
              need no farther introduction on our part.
              This being as we understand, the composer’s
              first opera, it was scarcely to be expected that
              the result would be epoch-making and, while
              the work shows no mean talent for compilation,
              there is certainly a falling away on the side
              of creative genius. We have here a produc-
              tion replete with all the " outward and visible
              signs ” of grand opera, its church scene with
              the inevitable bells, its triumphal march, its
              interspersion of ballet, and its tragic finale;
              but all these ingredients are such as require
              to be scored with sweeping power and vivid
              contrast, and we venture to think that M.
              Sinadino does not altogether meet these require-
              ments. He has given us a wealth of dainty
              music, full of delicate nuances and pleasing
              romances, but it is clear that he has yet to
              learn how to make full use of his orchestra
              and how, in the heavier movements, to stimu-
              late the senses and impart his message in
              crisp and penetrating outbursts. He leads
              up very well to the more involved passages
              but has evident difficulty in sustaining the
              " ensemble. " This feature is especially no-
              ticeable in the first act, which to some degree
              may be said to want life and firmness of pur-
              pose ; it elicits some fair opportunities, inclu-
              ding a quartet of marked merit, and introduces
              the meeting and subsequent mutual passion of
              tho Dogaressa (Signa. Bellincioni) and Stellio,
              the Pisan Ambassador to Venice (Sig. J. Palet).</p>

              <p>M. Sinadino is strongly imbued with a
              Wagnerian tendency, and this influence is
              displayed particularly throughout Act II,
              which, while being unquestionably the best
              act of the opera, is far too redolent of Tann-
              hauser and Lohengrin to be set down as
              purely intuitive; the distant trumpets and
              the heralding of the Doge’s approach follow
              too closely the huntsmen’s horns (Act I, Sc. 2)
              and the clarions (Act III) in Tannhauser. Then
              the chorus of Venetians denouncing Stellio
              is very much on the lines of the climax of
              Act III of the same opera, even to the positions
              taken up by the performers. All this, however,
              in no way detracts from the many exceedingly
              good effects which M. Sinadino obtains in this
              second act. The curtain rises to a graceful
              minuet air, but with the appearance of the
              Dogaressa, who has a pretty solo, the music
              becomes more complex, with an undercurrent
              of strong motif. The entry of the Doge
              (Sig. Nicolay) is scored with much grandeur
              and expression and requires only to be original
              to be a true masterpiece. The scene, however,
              is much too protracted; the populace start
              to welcome their chiefs when he must be an
              unconscionable distance off. There follows
              then a sort of allegorical ballet, danced to
              a valse movement and savouring somewhat
              of Drury Lane. The act proceeds with the
              discovery of Stellio’s indiscretions and his
              consequent disgrace, and terminates with the
              flight of the Dogaressa after her lover.</p>

              <p>To Act III, there is a very beautiful over-
              ture, exquisitely rendered under Sig. Zuccani’s
              bâton. It is well orchestrated and proved one
              of the finest portions of the opera. The scene is
              now laid on the terrace of a Pallazzo by night
              and we find the Dogaressa awaiting Stellio,
              who arrives, rather tardily, and his retreat
              having eventually been discovered, he is stabbed
              by order of the Doge's men. To build a whole
              act on such meagre foundations must, not un-
              naturally, have taxed M. Sinadino to the utter-
              most and, although he makes good use of a very
              Wagnerian motif on the string instruments,
              there are several drags, which not all Signa.
              Bellineloni’s efforts, with the valuable aid of
              Sig. Palet, could eliminate. True, each of them
              have pleasing arias and the love duet rises to
              a high pitch of efficiency ; but on the whole
              (and this applies throughout the opera) the
              situations are too thin and few to justify the
              length of the action, and either big cuts or
              an elaboration of the plot are needed before
              the intrinsic value of the work is to be gauged.
              Signa Bellincioni, Sigri. Pallet and Nibolay,
              no less than Maestro Zuccani, spared no pains
              to give full effect to their several tasks, while
              Signa. Zeppilli and Sig. Pasquale were well
              cast for the respective roles of Bellarmo and
              Bianca, the confidante. The chorus have not (
              very lengthy work but what there was of it
              was hard and proved rather too much for
              them. We have no fault to find with the
              ballet, whose dancing was as graceful as their
              appearance. The mise-en-scene was very good,
              though rather too ambitious for the interior
              of St. Mark's (Act I) and the full expanse
              of the Piazzetta (Act II) looks palpably unreal
              when set in miniature on the Zizinia stage.</p>

              <p>There was a large number of guests at the
              rehearsal, and to judge by the warm approval
              they expressed, we may safely forecast a big
              success for to-night’s premiere.</p></div>

              <div><head>NOTICE TO OUR READERS.</head>

              Monday next being New Year’s Day, the
              Egyptian Gazette will not be published on
              that day.</div>





              BERLITZ SCHOOLS OF LANGUAGES,






              <div><head>NOTES FROM PORT SAID.</head>
              <head>HOW 'XMAS WAS SPENT.</head>

              <head>GREAT CHANGE IN CLIMATE.</head>
              <p>(From our Correspondent).
              Port Said, Thursday.
              Asked his opinion of Port Said, Mark Twain
              once remarked, "It is a good town—to be out
              of !" This appears to have been the opinion of
              many of the English residents during the
              celebration of ’Xmas. For those who did not
              leave the town for the gaieties of Cairo, there
              were the usual dinners, smoking concerts,
              dances, 'Xmas trees, and children’s parties.</p>

              <p>Services were held on 'Xmas morning at the
              various churches in the town. In the afternoon,
              the patients of the Lady Strangford Hospital
              were entertained by a conjuring performance
              and variety concert, at which many of the
              English residents were present.</p>

              <p>The football match, Mr. Chessman’s Eleven
              v. Maltese, ended in a draw, no goals being
              scored on either side.</p>

              <p>Following the spell of wet weather last week
              we have experienced what might be almost
              termed an English 'Xmas. Suez has had an
              even more unique experience in having snow
              on Mount Attaka. Old European residents in
              the Canal say that there has been a great
              change in the climate during the last twenty
              or thirty years. Passengers coming from India
              and China have been very much struck with
              the change in the temperature, and not a few
              have remarked that it is a foretaste of what
              they will find in England.</p></div>

              <div><head>PLENTY OF WARSHIPS.</head>

              We have been quite inundated with war-
              ships of late. H.M.S. Diana arrived here
              last week, evidently with the intention of re-
              maining for some time. On Tuesday morning,
              H.M.S. Euryalus arrived from Australia, where
              she has been stationed for the last two years.
              Admiral Sir Arthur D. Fanahawe, late Com-
              mander of the Australian Squadron, disem-
              barked at Suez for Cairo, and re-embarked
              today for Portsmouth.</div>

              <div><head>RUSSIAN CRUISER.</head>
              <p>The Russian cruiser Cesarevitch, part of the
              crew of which mutinied in the Indian Ocean,
              arrived here to-day. The Russian transport
              Livonia, with part of the crew of the protected
              cruiser Oleg, left on Tuesday evening for
              Lihau.</p>

              <p>The French cruiser which took out to Indo-
              China the submarines Esturgeon and Perle,
              also arrived to-day.</p>

              <p>The Dutch cruiser Koenigen Wilhelmina
              arrived from Algiers en route for the Dutch
              East Indies.</p></div>

              <div><head>REINFORCEMENTS FOR YEMEN.</head>
              The Turkish transport Adana left for
              Hodeidah with re-inforcements for Marshal
              Faizi Pasha in his operations against the rebels
              in the Yemen.</div>

              <div><head>NEW P. & 0. LINER</head>
              The new P. & 0. liner Delhi arrived at
              Port Said on Tuesday evening, under the com-
              mand of Capt. J.D. Andrews. Her engines have
              8,000 h.p. with a speed of 18 knots. Among
              the passengers was Lord Hawke, the famous
              English cricketer.</div>

              <div><head>DOCTOR REWARDED.</head>
              Dr. Pressat, the well-known medical officer
              of the Suez Canal Co., who carried out exten-
              sive sanitary measures against malaria at
              Ismailia, has received one of tho special prizes
              awarded by the French Academy of Sciences
              for his original work, "La paludisme et les
              moustiques."</div>

              <div><head>LUXOR</head>
              <p>(From our Correspondent.)
              Luxor, Thursday.</p>

              <p>Never before at this time of the year has
              Luxor been so fall of visitors.</p>

              <p>On Sunday, 24th inst., the English Church
              was well attended, and a most interesting
              sermon was preached by the Rev. Professor
              Sayce on 1 Cor. XIII. 9. "We know in part."
              There were forty communicants on Christmas
              Day at the two celebrations, and the preacher
              was the Rev. A. W. Gross, chaplain, and the
              offertory for the Luxor Hospital for Natives
              amounted to 11.13.10. Bishop Potter, of New
              York, celebrated on Dec. 27 (St. John’s Day).
              Over one hundred visitors sat down to the
              excellent fare provided at the Luxor Hotel on
              Christmas Day, and the "small dance" in the
              evening was well attended, and very enjoyable.</p>

              <p>The Sporting Club held its first Gymkhana
              of the season (in aid of the local charities)
              to-day, and 80 Europeans paid for admis-
              sion, while the natives from the town and
              neighbourhood came, as usual, in great force.
              The racing was excellent, and the committee
              are to be congratulated on the arrangements
              made for the amusement of guests and the
              benefit of several worthy objects. The local police, ,
              under the superintendence of the mrowan,
              preserved the usual good order on the course
              and its approaches.</p>

              <p>The following was the programme:-
              1	Bishareen Arab Race (Sack)
              2	Native Water-Carriers’ Race
              8 Ladies’ and Gentlemen’s Race.
              4 Donkey Boys’ Race
              5 Ladies’ and Gentlemen’s Goolah Pegging Race,
              6	Buffalo	Race
              7	Horse	Race    	Natives
              6 Camel	Race</p>

              <p>Messrs.	Western and Edleman were starters
              and the judges were Rev. A. W. Gross, Dr.
              Snowden, and Mr. Saville. Dr. Saunders was
              clerk of the course.</p></div>

              <div><head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>

              <head>AFFAIR BEFORE TRIBUNAL.</head>

              <head>PROPOSAL REGARDING CREDITORS.</head>

              <p>The Sucreries case came up before the
              Chambre des Faillites of the Cairo Mixed Tri-
              bunal today. The Court was composed as
              follows; president, Judge Tuck; assessors, Judge
              Coghlan, Wierdels, Youssef Bey Aziz, and
              Moh. Bey Rassim. M. Musséri was European
              assessor and the Government was represented
              by Bairam Bey.</p>

              <p>Maitre Carton de Wiart informed the Tri-
              bunal that the following proposal had been
              accepted by the shareholders of the Sucreries:—</p>

              <p>"All Creditors, except mortgaged and pri-
              vileged creditors, are to get 80 per cent. of
              their claims, payable in debentures, bearing 5
              per cent interest from January. 1, 1910, and
              redeemable in 60 years at 25 per cent. premium.
              Up to January 1, 1910, the debenture holders
              are to receive a minimum of 2 per cent interest,
              guaranteed by sums deposited at the Banque
              de France.”</p>

              <p>Some discussion followed, the Court remark-
              ing that these proposals had not been formally
              put before it, and that the question of the
              railway, etc, had not bean touched.</p>

              <p>Maitre Carton de Wiart applied for a special
              meeting of creditors to deal with these points,
              and after further discussion the hearing was
              postponed for a week.</p></div>

              <div><head>REDUCTION IN POSTAL RATES.</head>

              <p>The following reductions in postal rates
              will come into force on January 1, 1906:</p>

              <p>1.	The inland registration fee on corres-
              pondence for Egypt and the Sudan will be
              reduced from 10 ms. to 6 ms.</p>

              <p>2.	The commission on inland money orders
              will be reduced from 4 ms. to 3 ms. for
              every LE. 1 or fraction thereof, the minimum
              commission being 10 milliemes.</p></div>

              <div><head>PAN-EGYPTIAN GAMES.</head>
              Pan-Egyptian Games are to be held at
              Cairo on the 9th, 10th, and 11th February
              next, under the auspices of the Hellenic
              Athletic Association "Iphitos" of Cairo, and
              under the patronage of the Hellenic Diplomatic
              Agent and Consul-General at Cairo. The games
              will be for amateurs only, and invitations to
              participate have been addressed to all the athle0
              tic and sporting clubs in Egypt. The programme
              of events is long and varied.</div>

              <div><head>GHEZIREH PALACE HOTEL.</head>
              <p>This hotel gave its first small dance of the
              season on Thursday night, and despite all
              the disadvantages of cold and distance, many
              people braved the elements in order to be
              present. The Ghezireh Palace has a great re-
              putation for its dances and entertainments.
              Indeed, no better background oould be found
              for pretty frocks and uniforms than its gor-
              geous halls and salons. Many dinner parties
              had been arranged for Thursday, and covers
              for over a hundred and twenty people had
              been laid. Mr. Curphy was host to fourteen
              guesrs, including the Hon. F. Morgan, the
              Hon. and Mrs. C. James, Mr. and Mrs. Heller,
              Mrs. Bailey, Mr. and Mrs. Rom, Miss Begg, ’
              and Mr. Spooner. Col. Gordon was entertain-
              ing Lieut. Col. Watson and Mr. Carter Wilson
              among others, and at Sir Hugh Smiley’s
              table were Capt. and Mrs. Rome and Crook-
              shank Pasha. Lady Sampson had a party of
              eight, among whom were Major Davidson and
              other officers of the Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers.
              Capt. Grant had a party of seven. Major
              and Mrs. Winn were entertaining friends, as
              also were Major Burnie, Mr. Horrold, Major
              Hessia, Mr. von Mohl, Mr. Bennett, Mr. Bink-
              ley, Capt. Wynham, and Mr. and Mlle Saber-
              casseaux. Many other guests arrived after
              dinner, and by ten o’clock dancing was in
              full swing to the strains of most seductive
              music.</p>

              <p>Mrs. Rom was looking her best in white
              net, the skirt having a deep flounce of white
              satin, and a trimming in which silver tinsel
              played an important part. The foil net bodice
              terminated in a folded corselet and sash of
              white satin. Miss Begg, who always has the
              best of times, was wearing very pale pink
              with lace insertions run through with pink
              ribbon. Mrs. Rome, whose wedding made such a
              sensation in the autumn, was in an artistic frock
              of soft blue, with a touch of the same colour
              in her hair. Mrs. Bailey was in pink, with an
              old-world tucker in the corsage, and Mrs.
              Heller was wearing a most becoming empire
              gown of black chiffon with appliquées of shad-
              ed pink roses on this skirt, and pink ribbons
              threaded in the lace decollatage. Mrs. Winn
              was in white, with many rufflings of ribbon and
              much fine lace, and had a pink rose tucked in
              her hair. Mrs. C. James was in turquoise blue
              silk with a sash of shaded chené ribbon, with a
              twist of blue threaded through her coiffure.
              Mrs, Maclean was in black, but made over
              white. Mrs. Allan Joseph brought Miss Joseph
              and her two girl friends, the latter both in
              white, while Miss Joseph was in pink crêpe-de-
              chine. Supper was served at about midnight,
              when over eighty refreshed themselves before
              dancing out the remainder of the programme.</p></div>

              <div><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>

              The Moss liner Rameses sailed yesterday
              afternoon for Liverpool via Malta, with pas-
              sengers, mails, and general cargo, including
              4,606 bales cotton.</div>

              <div><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>

              <p>Prince Charles, Duke of Sudermania, the
              second son of the Crown Prince of Sweden,
              is arriving in Egypt on board a Swedish man-
              of-war, which is due at Alexandria on the
              5th January. On his arrival the Prince will
              proceed to Cairo.</p>

              <p>Prince Christian of Hesse, Captain Mayer,
              and several of the officers of the German
              corvette Charlotte were entertained to dinner
              and a Christmas Tree fête at the German
              Consulate, Alexandria, yesterday evening by
              Herr Hellwig, the acting German Consul.</p>

              <p>Lord de Clifford and party have reserved
              rooms at the Savoy.</p>

              <p>The Right Rev. C. Potter, Bishop of New
              York, and party will be back at the Savoy
              about the 15th January from Upper Egypt.</p>

              <p>Mr. and Lady Victoria Machell came up
              from Port Said by the 12.45 am. train to
              Cairo on Thursday and were met by a
              number of friends and colleagues of the Ad-
              viser of the Ministry of the Interior at the Bab
              el-Gedid station, where they arrived at 5 p.m.
              to meet with a warm welcome.</p>

              <p>Among other visitors staying at Ghe-
              sireh Palace Hotel are Viscount and Vicount-
              ess de Sinety, Admiral Sir Arthur Fan-
              shawe, K.C.B., Colonel and Mrs Collingwood,
              Mme I. de Brandys and family, Mr. and
              Mrs. Pauling and party, Mr. and Mrs. Sparrow,
              Mr. C. H. Luckham, R.N., Mr. and Mme Sis-
              bercaseaux, M. de Borros, Mr. and Mrs. J. H.
              Brockbank, Mr. and Mrs. Neville, Mr. Hamp-
              son, Miss Leigh and Miss Berry, Miss Gee,
              Mr. R. R. Beard.</p>

              <p>Judge Heggen, of Mansourah, has arrived
              at Mema House for a change of air.</p>

              <p>Capt. H. B.Montagu and Capt. T. C. Wood,
              of H.M.S. Diana, lying at Port Said, are
              spending a few days at Mena House.</p>

              <p>Col. Augustus Hill and Miss Hill, who have
              been regular visitors to Mena House for many
              years, and the Hon. Gerald Otho Fitzgerald,
              accompanied by General Sir G. Fitzgerald, will
              arrive shortly to spend the winter there.</p>

              <p>This week’s arrivals at the Savoy Hotel,
              Cairo, include: Mr. C. P. Beebe; Mr. Franklin
              Beeba, Boston; Mr. and Mrs. Muggeridge,
              London; Mr. and Mrs. G. F. London and party,
              Glasgow; Mr. and Mrs. W. G. Van Horne,
              Alexandria; Mr. F. A. Belleville, London;
              Mr. Alexander Leith, London; The Misses P.
              and D. Rogers, London; Major Hawker Bey,
              Suakin ; Lady Oppenheimer, Frankfort; Mrs.
              Spencer Ledyard, London; Mrs. Brigstoke,
              Isle of Wight; Madame N. Gulbenkian, London;
              Mr. Essayan, London; Mrs. York and Misses
              York, London; Capt. and Mrs. C.K. Morgan,
              Cairo; Mr. and Mrs. E. W. Roperts.</p>

              <p>Lady Wraxall begs to thank all those who
              so generously subscribed for her children’s
              relief at Christmas, also Mrs. Robinson, for-
              merly of the Scottish Mission, and Mr. W. T.
              Whitfield, who raised the subscription on her
              behalf.</p>

              <p>Emin Bey, Turkish Consul General in
              London, is staying in Cairo.</p>

              <p>M. Michel Sinadino has contributed £1 to
              the funds of the Rudolph Home as a dis-
              pensation from paying New Year's visits.</p>

              <p>Mr. and Mrs. Lang-Anderson and family are
              going to Cairo to-day to pass the New Year
              holidays at Shepheard’s.</p>

              <p>The following passengers left by the Anglo-
              American Company’s S. S. Mayflower for the
              Nile trip yesterday:- Mr. and Mrs. M. J.
              Lawrence, Herr Consul and Fran Martens, Mr.
              and Mrs. Proppe, Mr. and Mme Roussella, Mr.
              and Mrs. A. L. Mumm, Mr. and Mrs. Louis
              Pennington, Mrs. John A. Wells, Mr. Jean-
              naire, Mrs. Zachariai.</p></div>

              <div><head>St. Mark’s, Alexandria.</head>
              <p>On Sunday, December 31, Services will be as
              under:</p>

              <p>8 a.m. Holy Communion.
              11 a.m. Matins, Litany and Sermon.
              6.15 p.m. Evensong and Sermon.</p>

              <p>There will be no watch-night service, but at
              the 6.15 p.m. service appropriate prayers will
              be offered, and hymns for New Year's Eve
              sung.</p>

              <p>On New Year’s Day the services will be:
              8 a.m. Holy Communion.
              11 a.m. Morning Prayer and Address.</p></div>

              <div><head>All Saints’ Church, Cairo.</head>
              <p>On December 31 (1st Sunday after Christ-
              mas) Services will be as under:</p>

              <p>Holy Communion	8.30	a.m.
              Morning Service	10.30	a.m.
              Children's Service	3.30	p.m
              Evening Service	6	p.m.
              Midnight Service end Celebration of
              Holy Communion	11.15	p.m.
              January 1st, 1906.
              Morning Service	10.30 a.m.
              Holy Communion after morning service
              CHARLES H. BUTCHER. Chaplain.</p></div>

            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
