<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">Enter today's date</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

              <div type= "LOCAL AND GENERAL">
                <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>

              <p>The Brindisi Mail.
              The mail will close at the G. P. O., Alex-
              andria, at 3.10 p.m. on Sunday.</p>

              <p>Death from Cold.
              The weather in Cairo remains unusually
              severe. A ghaffir dropped dead at his post
              on Tuesday night from heart failure caused by
              cold.</p>

              <p>Khedivial Sporting Club.
              Owners are reminded that entries for the
              Grand National Steeplechase (value £E 100)
              and the International Handicap (value £B 100),
              to be run at the Second Winter Meeting close
              on January 1.</p>

              <p>Collision at Assouan.
              A small steamboat was a few days ago
              crossing the Nile near Elephantine Island,
              Assouan, with a number of tourists on board,
              when she came into collision with a boat,
              belonging to a hotel company, and sank. The
              passengers, who were 11 in number, were
              saved.</p>

              <p>Egyptian Institute.
              The election of officers to the Egyptian
              Institute for 1906 has taken place. Fakhry
              Pasha remains president ; the vice-presidents
              are Ahbate Pasha and Yacoub Pasha Artin. M.
              Barois is treasurer and librarian. Walter Innes
              Bey assistant seretary, and the committee for
              publications comprises Piot Bey and MM. Bay
              and Fourtan.</p>

              <p>Review of Egyptian Troops.
              A review of Egyptian troops will take place
              at Abbassieh at 3 p. m. on January 8, the
              anniversary of H. H the Khedive’s accession.
              All who desire admittance to the reserved
              enclosures should address themselves to the
              A. A. G. War Office, stating whether they are
              residents or visitors.</p>

              <p>Native Court.
              The trial of the Greek cheese hawker, who
              fatally, stabbed a native carpenter in the Labbane
              quarter of Alexandria a few weeks ago, took
              place at the Native Court of Alexandria, the
              man being an Ottoman subject. The accused,
              who was defended by Ali Bey Assem, was sen-
              tenced to two years' imprisonment.</p>

              <p>The Meteorological Service.
              The meteorological observations over Egypt
              and the Sudan have now been made at nearly
              all stations for four or more years, and the
              information obtained makes it possible to
              undertake more thoroughly the study of the
              factors which determine the Nile Flood, in
              co-operation with the Meteorological Services
              of surrounding countries. In 1906 it is proposed
              to devote more time to this question, in order
              to see what information from other areas can
              be most usefully employed in estimating the
              probable strength of the rains in Abyssinia.</p>

              <p>Garrison Directory.
              We have received a copy of the December
              issue of the Garrison Directory, published by
              the authority of the G. O. C. in Egypt, which
              is bulkier than its predecessors and contains
              a mass of information useful to residents in
              Egypt. The January edition will be ready for
              sale about the 15th prox. Should any errors or
              omissions be observed in the present edition it
              is requested that these be at once brought to
              the notice of the “Clerk-in-charge, The
              Garrison Directory, British Head Quarters,
              Cairo,” not later than the 31st inst.</p>

              <p>African World Annual.
              We have received the "African World”
              Christmas Annual, a bulky production of about
              300 folio pages packed full of interesting
              information regarding every part of Africa,
              from the Cape to Cairo. Though the contents
              are mainly devoted to South African mining,
              a section which is of the utmost value to those
              interested in these ventures, space is found
              for a whole series of ably written and specially
              contributed articles, dealing with almost every
              phase of African activity—whether it be on
              mining, or on sport, politics, and travel. The
              literary value of the publication is very high
              and it is most profusely illustrated with photo-
              graphs and sketches. The editors and compilers,
              Messrs. Leo Weinthal, Hartley Knight, and
              Moses Roberts, are to be congratulated on a
              marvellously fine production. It costs 2s, and
              should be in the hands of all those interested
              in any part of this continent.</p></div>

              <div type= "MOERIS HOTEL">
                <head>MOERIS HOTEL.</head>
              On Lake Moeril
              In connection with the Karoon Hotel
              Fayoum.
              For particulars apply Mr. Tasco, Fayoum.</div>








              Isherwood’s Cairo Cigarettes.
              The reputation which these Cigarettes have
              gained in the past stands unrivalled to-day,
              because it is well-known that constant care
              and attention is devoted to supplying really
              first-class Cigarettes only.
              Between the British Consulate end Turf Club.

              EDEN PALACE HOTEL
              Cairo.
              NOTED FOR ITS EXCELLENT CUISINE.

              Anglo-American Nile Steamers
              Hotel Company
              River Tranport of Goods between Alexandria and Cairo.
              THREE SAILINGS A WEEK.
              Agents at Alexandria
              ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO., LTD.












              <div type= "EGYPT'S FRONTIER">
                <head>EGYPT’S FRONTIER.</head>
              <head>THE PORTE’S CLAIMS.</head>
              <head>A TURCO-EGYPTIAN DISPUTE.</head>

              <p>A dispute between the Egyptian and Turkish
              Governments respecting the frontier separat-
              ing Egypt from the Benghazi District is report-
              ed by a Constantinople correspondent. Last
              year the Turkish Government caused barracks
              for a company of infantry to be erected at
              the further end of the Gulf of Sollom, from
              which the line of demarcation between Egypt
              and the district of Benghazi starts. The
              barracks, however, were erected at a point
              situated a little beyond the Turkish frontier,
              and the Khedive's Government therefore pro-
              tested against this encroachment by Turkish
              troops on Eyptian territory.</p>

              <p>To this the Porte only answered that there
              could be no question of any encroachment on
              a foreign soil on the part of Turkey, “since
              the villayet (province) of Egypt formed an
              integral part of the Ottoman Empire.”</p>

              <p>The sophistry of this argument did not
              escape the Egyptian Government. In order
              both to force the Turkish garrison in the
              barracks to quit Egyptian soil and to restore
              to Egypt her rights of territorial sovereignty
              not only over the entire district of Sollom but
              also over a district of about 250 kilometres to
              the west of that point, it is causing an Egyp-
              tian military post to be constructed at the
              farther end of the Bay of Bomba.</p>

              <p>The erection, therefore, of this Egyptian
              military post at Bomba will have for result
              the acquisition by Egypt of a considerable area.
              The frontier between Egypt and the Turkish
              district of Benghazi, which began, as the maps
              indicate, at Sollon, will now start from the
              Bay of Bomba, that is to say, will include
              about 250 kilometres more in the direction of
              the west.</p>

              <p>Recently the Turkish Council of Ministers
              discussed this question at great length, and
              decided that the Grand Vizier should address a
              communication directly to the Egyptian
              Government calling on it to give up the project.
              The Governor of Benghazi, Hilmy Pasha, has,
              on his side, received orders, to oppose by any
              means he may consider necessary the erection
              by the Egyptians of a military post at Bomba,
              supposing the Khedivial Government should
              refuse to take into consideration the communi-
              cation of the Grand Vizier.</p>

              <p>According to Turkish intelligence, an Egyp-
              tian despatch boat has been chosen to convey
              to Bomba the Egyptian soldiers whose duty it
              will be to erect the military post and thus to
              isolate from Benghazi the Turkish barracks at
              Sollom.</p>

              <p>The above statements emanate from Con-
              stantinople and we have not obtained con-
              firmation of them from any authorised Egyptian
              source.</p></div>

              <div type= "COUNCIL OFMINISTERS">
                <head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
              <p>The following decisions were taken by the
              Council of Ministers which met at Abdeen
              Palace yesterday under the presidency of H.H.
              the Khedive: —</p>

              <p>1 To open a credit of L E 40,000 for two
              coal quays at Alexandria.</p>

              <p>2	Togrant a credit of L.E. 1,000 to the
              Khedivial Agricultural Society to enable it to
              establish one branch in Dakahlieh and one in
              Behers.</p>

              <p>3	To appoint Hussein Bey Rushdi as Coun-
              sellor to the Native Court of Appeal.</p>

              <p>4	Approval of the Budget provisions for
              the administrations not in the Budget.</p>

              <p>5 Approval of the new regulations of the
              Ministry of Public Instruction for the School
              of Medicine, Law School, and primary certi-
              ficate.</p>

              <p>6	Reduction of the charge for the registra-
              tion of letters to 5 milliemes and the charge
              for postal orders to 3 milliemes and a half per-
              L E 1 tor the Interior.</p>

              <p>7	Nomination of Sheikh Ahmed Moh, Der-
              wish, Ulema of Al Azhar, to the Cadiship of
              Al Arish.</p></div>

              <div type= "NILE-RED SEA RAILWAY">
                <head>NILE-RED SEA RAILWAY.</head>

              <p>The Khedivial Mail S.S. Dakahlieh will
              convey the visitors to the inauguration of the
              Nile-Red Sea Railway to Port Sudan and back.
              The foreign diplomatic agents and the Minis-
              ters have been invited, with the following nine
              members of the Legislative Council : Char-
              warbi Pasha, Ismail Pasha Abaza, Hassan
              Pasha Abd el Razzak, Toulba Bey, Seoudi
              Hassan Bey Madkour, Ibrahim Bey Murad,
              Ahmed Bey Yehia, and Tamam Bey Kassab.</p></div>

              <div type= "SUDAN APPOINTMENTS">
                <head>SUDAN APPOINTMENTS.</head>
              <p>Mr. E. Eonus has been appointed Director
              of Agriculture and Lands Department.</p>

              <p>El Kaimakam G. S. Nickerson Bey. Junior
              Inspector Sennar Province, to be Senior In-
              spector Sennar Province.</p>

              <p>The undermentioned gentlemen are appoint-
              ed surveyors in the Surveys Department.
              Mr. W. S. M Vines and Mr. W. R. Field.</p>

              <p>Mr. A. de R. Gordon is appointed Vete-
              rinary Surgeon, in the Veterinary Department
              ("Sudan Gazette”).</p></div>

              <div type= "NILE COLD STORAGE CO.">

                <head>NILE COLD STORAGE CO.</head>

              <p>An extraordinary general meeting of the
              Nile Cold Storage Company, Limited, will be
              held at the offices, 63 to 74, Palmerston House,
              Old Broadstreet, London, on January 4, at
              twelve o’clock noon, for the purpose of effect-
              ing certain alterations in the articles of associa-
              tion. The details appear in our advertising
              columns.</p></div>

              <div type= "A KHEDIVIAL PRINCESS'S DEATH">

                <head>A KHEDIVIAL PRINCESS’S DEATH.</head>

              <head>ENQUIRY OPENED AT YILDIZ KIOSK.</head>

              <head>DJELLALEDDIN PASHA’S PROTEST TO THE SULTAN.</head>

              <p>The death of the Khedivial Princess who
              was the wife of General Ahmed. Djelaleddin
              Pasha and the sister of Prince Omar Pasha
              and Prince Djemil Pasha Toussoun, is still
              fresh in the minds of all, for the funeral, which
              took place at Alexandria, was one of the most
              solemn and largely attended inhumations that
              have taken place here for years past. Her body
              rests in the Mosque of Nebi Daniel.</p>

              <p>Since her death her husband, who for more
              than ten years was the most powerful and
              honorable of the Sultan's advisors, has re-
              sided in Egypt and resisted all the blandish-
              ments of the Sublime Porte to induce him to
              go back to Stamboul. His obstinacy has led, it
              is said, to the confiscation of his estates in
              Turkey, and now the Sultan has determined to
              blacken the character of his erstwhile favorite
              by ordering a commission to sit at Yildiz
              Kiosque in order to enquire into the circum-
              stances attending his wife's death. The Pasha’s
              case is fully set out in the telegram which he
              despatched to Tahsin Pasha, first secretary to
              the Sultan, on the 26th inst. The text of this
              despatch is as follows .—</p>

              <p>Je viens d'apprendre par les journaux l’en-
              quête ouverte au palais de Yildiz au aujet de
              la légère opération chirurgicale que la prin-
              cesse, ma très regrettée épouse, avait subie,
              aprés consultation et décision de quelques som-
              mités médicales de la Capitale, un an et demi
              avant sa mort et à laquelle assistaient égale-
              ment sa mère sa soeur et son beau-père.</p>

              <p>Je considère comme un devoir saoré d'aider
              de toss mes moyens à toute to démarche qui pour-
              rait constituer un hummage à la mémoire de la
              regrettée défunte, en facilitant la déconverte de
              la vérité en tout ce qui la concerne; Le soupçon,
              l'évidence même d'une intention personnelle-
              ment désobligeante pour moi, ne-saurait m’em-
              pêcher d'accomplir ce devoir sacré. Aussi
              est-ce avec empressement que je viens surgérer
              les moyens les plus propices à atteindre la but
              proposé.</p>

              <p>La défunte princesse est inhumée an Egypte
              et son cercueil porte tonjours les soellés qui,
              conformément au règlement régissant le trans-
              fert des corps, ont été apposés par les antorités
              po'icières de la ville de Cannes, cu elle a
              rendu le dernier soupir. Tous ses parents,
              l'illusure famille á laquelle elle appartenait,
              sont domiciliés dans ce pays et j'y suis établi
              moi-même, principal intéressé. La haute re-
              nommés de justice et d’impartialité des tri-
              bunaux égyptiens demeurant au-dessus de
              toute contestation il serait donc tout-à-fait
              naturel de poursuivre ce procès en Egypte, ce
              qui assurerait l’exaltation entière de la vérité.</p>

              <p>Pourtant, si par une considération queloon-
              que le recours aux tribunaux égyptiens était
              jugé inopportun on rourrait parfaitement
              déférer le cas à la justice française, la prince se
              étant morte en France. Au surplus, je suis
              prêt à me présenter à la justice de tout pays
              civilisé où l'indépendance des tribunaux se
              tronve assurée.</p>

              <p>Mais la manière par laquelle l’enquête est
              inaugurée à Constantinople, la constitution
              d’une commission au palais de Yildiz, qui ne
              devrait en rien intervenir dans une affaire
              judiciaire, la pression exercée sur certains mé-
              decins (parmi lesquels d’auouns n’avaient d’ail-
              leurs jamais examiné la défunte princesse)pour
              leur faire apposer leurs signatures au-dassous
              d'un rapport préslablement préparé, les mena-
              ces proférées à cette occasion constituent au-
              tant de symptômes indiquant que l’enquête
              poursuivie à Constantinople marque, dans son
              origine même, de cette incérité dans la recher-
              che de la vérité qui constitue la condition
              essentielle de toute justice régulière.</p>

              <p>Aussi, il devieut indispensable dans l’intérêt
              même du but pousuivi de trausférer le procès
              devant une justice inaccessible à aucune ingé-
              rence et dont la procédure normale ne saurait
              subir aucune déviation.</p>

              <p>Cette proposition ne peut qu’être adoptée,
              s’il existe la moindre impartialité dans l’en-
              quête inaugurêe. Le triomphe de ceux qui la
              poursuiventrerait incontestables’ils parvenaient
              à obtenir une condemnation d’un tribunal
              jugeant en pleine possession de son indépen-
              dance. Le refus, au contraire, de porter l'affaire
              devant une justice impartiale, découvrirait de
              suite le but caché qui ne peut être autre chose
              que de porter une grave atteinte à ma dignité
              et à mon honneur. Ce sont là justement les
              seuls biens auquels je tiens dans l’exil volon-
              taire que je me suis imposé. En présence d’une
              pareille entreprise qui sous imposé d'une
              procès absurde, équivaut à déclarer une guerre
              ouverte contre mon honneur, toute considera-
              tion de convenance, tout souvenir d’anciennes
              bienveillances cessent d'avoir leur raison d'être.
              La responsabilité de cette nouvelle situation
              ne peut révenir qu’a ceux qui m’obligent de
              me départir de la neutralité que je me suis
              imposée vis-à-vis du vrai instigateur de ces
              intrignes. J'accepterai le combat et j'attendral
              avec confiance les hostilités pour défendre mon
              honneur et lui conserver dans le monde
              l’estime et la considération dont je suis fier
              da le voir entouré. Ce sera une nouvelle
              occasion pour manifester la puissance morale
              de l’honneur et affirmer son triomphe contre
              toute force qui voudrait l'écraser injustement.</p>

              <p>An Englishman, who knew the Pasha at
              Constantinople, thus describes him:-</p>

              <p>Djellaleddin Pasha was for years foremost
              and prime favorite among all the Sultan’s
              subjects, and fully deserved the trust
              reposed in him as an honorable and upright
              gentleman. His downfall, therefore, came as a
              shock to all who knew him, the greater,
              perhaps, for that the report added that
              he had been denounced by the Secret Police
              of the Palace, a force which he himself created
              and organised, and of which, among many
              offices, he has always been the working chief.
              A remarkable and singularly fascinating per-
              sonality, Ahmed Pasha’s most salient quality
              was ever an absolutely whole-hearted devotion
              to his master and when at last the enemies who
              ever dog the footsteps of Royal favorites
              succeeded in alienating from him Abdul
              Hamid’s confidence and affection, the cir-
              cumstance was received aa indicating a further
              sinister advance in the progress of that be-
              setting "manie de la persécution” which has
              for years haunted the gloomy potentate of
              Yildiz. During his long term of honored ser-
              vice Ahmed Pasha enjoyed an absolutely
              unique position in the Yildiz set. Privileges
              have been his which no other Turkish function-
              ary would have dared to solicit. Of late years, for
              instance, social communion between Turks and
              Europeans in the capital has been tacitly, and in
              some cases openly, prohibited. Yet Ahmed was
              a prominent member of the “English" club,
              and to which practically all the English colony
              belongs in common with the chief members of
              other European communities. Almost every
              day, indeed, Fridays excepted, during the
              many years I knew him, Ahmed Pasha took
              his place at the Bridge table—for Bridge was
              popular in Constantinople long before it was
              heard of in Europe, and it may be said that he
              is both a fine player and a good loser. It has
              often been suggested that this licensed associa-
              tion with Europeans was not wholly foreign to
              his functions as chief of the Secret Police. As to
              this, however, it may be said that all who have
              known the Pasha were penetrated with the
              sense of his complete honorability. In proof
              of this is the fact that when Abdul Hamid
              sought to end his differences with the
              chiefs in Paris of the ” Young Turkey ”
              party he employed in vain one intermediary
              after another until it was intimated to him
              that the services of Ahmed Djellaleddin as
              envoy would procure the desired result. The
              Pasha, therefore, was sent to Paris and on
              his representations the ” Young Turkey ”
              leaden complied with the Sultan’s invitation
              that they should return to Constantinople and
              their allegiance. It is noteworthy in this
              connection that Ahmed's influence with his
              master has sufficed to assure to them the
              immunity that he promised. It is within my
              knowledge that on several occasions he has
              been urged to diverge from this line of con-
              duct, and that at the risk of that loss
              of favor which has now overtaken him he
              invariably refused to put his hand to any
              unworthy action. Oddly enough, until now
              this inflexibility has served rather than injur-
              ed him in his master’s eyes : for the Sultan,
              though freely using spies and traitors, has
              a wholesome contempt for such gentry. Cover-
              ed with honors, only before his fall from
              favor recently, indeed, the Sultan bestowed
              on him the last and highest decoration in his
              gift.</p></div>

              <div type= "CHANGES AMONG JUDGES">

                <head>CHANGES AMONG JUDGES.</head>

              <p>There are some impending changes afmong
              the judges of the Mixed Courts. We hear that
              Joseph Bey Cherakian, judge of the Alexandria
              Mixed Tribunal, will be appointed counsellor to
              the Mixed Court of Appeal. Mohamed Bey Musta-
              pha, judge of the Mansourah Mixed Tribunal,
              will be transferred to Alexandria in place of
              Judge Cherakian. Ragbeb Bey Badr, also a
              judge of the Mansourah Tribunal, will be
              transferred to Cairo, in place of Hassein Bey
              Rouchdi. Abdel Messih Bey Semeika, judge
              of the Zagazig Native Tribunal, and Mohamed
              Bey Sidky, president of the Keneh Native
              Tribunal, will be appointed judges of the
              Mixed Tribunal at Mansourah.</p></div>

              <div type= "CAIRO MIXED COURTS">

                <head>CAIRO MIXED COURTS.</head>

              <p>The following are the names of the judges’
              commercial assessors elected for 1906-7 in the
              Mixed Tribunal, Cairo :—
              Mendel Giacomo, Italian, to sit in February
              Ebano.C.A,	„	„	„	March
              Cattaoui Bey, J, Austrian, „ April
              Henriques, R Q, British,	„	„	May
              Birchee, André, French,	„	„	June
              Stross, R, Austrian,	„	„ 	July
              Pelizaeus, W., German,	„	August
              Zouro, C, Greek,	„	September
              Xenakis,C., „	„	„	October
              Mosseri, G. Italian, •__ „	„	November
              Battemberg, Ch., French,	„	December
              Williamson, .J.W-., British,	„	„	January</p>

              <p>The following are the names of the “sup-
              pléanta” ;—
              Ablitt, Walker, British, to	be called	1st
              Pitelle, Louis, French,	„ . „	2nd
              Dombra, Emile, „	„	„	3rd
              Cattaoui Bey, M., Austrian	„	„	4th
              Sterzing, Otto, German,	,,	„	6th
              Rolo, Robert, British,	6th
              Chelmis, Ange, Greek,	„	„	‘	7th
              Lonsdorpper, N., German,	„	„	8th
              Rostovitz Bey, A., Greek, „ 4	9th
              Hasselbach, C., German	„	„	10th
              Beer, Alfredo, Italian,	„	„	11th
              Padova, Mario, „	„	„	12th</p></div>

              <div type= "STEAMER MOVEMENTS">

              <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
              <p>The Moss liner Seti sailed yesterday after-
              noon from Malta and is due here on Sunday
              evening with passengers, mails and general
              cargo. </p></div>

              <div type= "CRISIS IN NEW YORK">
              <head>CRISIS IN NEW YORK.</head>
              <head>A SEVERE SLUMP.</head>
              <head>UNEASINESS INvMONEY MARKET.</head>

              <p>(Gazette's Special Service.)
              London. Thursday, Dec. 28.
              A severe slump has been caused at New
              York owing to day-to-day money being at 90
              per cent, and a feeling of considerable unea-
              siness prevails on the subject of Friday's
              settlement
              The ‘World’’ states that notwithstanding
              public assertions Lawson is believed to be
              gaining by the boom in copper.</p></div>

              <div type= "RESCUE OF A CREW">

                <head>RESCUE OF A CREW.</head>

              <p>(From our Correspondent).
              Port Said, Thursday.
              The Dutch steamer Willis arrived at Port
              Said at 10.5 p.m. on Tuesday, bound from
              Rotterdam, via Marseilles, for Java. The
              captain reports that on the 23rd inst. he was
              signalled to by the Greek S.S. Annikar, which
              was in such a bad state that the S.S Willis
              stayed in the vicinity all night and took her
              crew on board in the early morning as the
              deck of the ship was under water and she was
              floating on the cargo.</p>

              <p>The S.S. Willis left the wreck in Lat. N.
              36' 45 and Long. E. 17’ 56'.</p></div>

              <div type= "DEATH OF MRS. MOND">

                <head>DEATH OF MRS. MOND.</head>
              <p>(From our Correspondent).
              Luxor, Thursday.
              Mrs. R. Mond died at 4 o’clock this morning
              after a short illness of only three days’ duration.
              The lady and her husband are well-known
              annual visitors to Egypt and great sympathy
              is expressed here for the widower in his be-
              reavement. Mr. Mond belongs to the family
              who have made Brunner Mond & Co, one of
              the largest manufacturing chemical firms in
              the world.</p></div>

              <div type= "SUPREME CONSULAR COURT">

                <head>SUPREME CONSULAR COURT.</head>
              <p>The trial of Gerasimo Agius before the
              Supreme Consular Court at Alexandria was
              concluded on the evening of the 27th inst.
              The jury found the accused guilty of unlaw-
              fully wounding two Greeks, Morselli and
              Delyannis, and of having attempted to murder
              Pietro Damiano, an Italian. On the latter
              count he was condemned to seven years’ penal
              servitude. The charges on the other count
              were withdrawn by the prosecution.</p>

              <p>Judge Cator is leaving for Cairo, probably to
              hear a civil case in regard to the administra-
              tion of the Debarro estate.</p></div>

              <div type= "EXPLOSION IN CAIRO">

                <head>EXPLOSION IN CAIRO.</head>
              <p>On Wednesday, three Jews, Saad Farag,
              Ibrahim Moussa, and Haim Fossi, were en-
              gaged in making fireworks and petards for the
              Accession Day fêtes (which take place on
              January 8) in a house at Haret el Yahoudi, in
              the Mousky quarter of Cairo, when a violent
              explosion took place. One of the walls collapsed
              and the unfortunate men were overwhelmed
              by the debris.</p>

              <p>Saad Farag was killed on the spot. Ibrahim
              Moussa, after being badly burnt about the
              hands and body, was injured by falling debris
              and is now in hospital. Fossi escaped with
              comparatively slight injuries. The police took
              speedy measures to extricate the men and to
              remove the debris. A procès-verbal estalished
              the fact that the explosion was due to acci-
              dental causes.</p></div>

              <div type= "PROVINCIAL KUTTABS">

                <head>PROVINCIAL KUTTABS</head>

              <p>(From our Correspondent).
              Zifta, Thursday.</p>

              <p>A meeting was held to-day, in a large tent
              near the Zifta Markaz, of the omdehs, mer-
              chants, and notables of the town and surround-
              ing villages. The Sub-Moudir of Gharbieh,
              Abdel Ghani Bey Shakir, the Mamour of Zifta,
              Hafez Effendi Amin, and many other notables
              were present. The Sub-Moudir opened the
              proceedings by a speech explaining the object
              of the gathering and urging them to help the
              kuttabs and their arifs, as many benefits were
              to be derived from them. The inspector of the
              kuttabs of Lower Egypt, Sheikh Mohamed
              Nassar, then said something as to the advant-
              ages of learning and education, their effect upon
              civilisation, the uses of the new kuttabs, and
              the necessity of spreading knowledge among
              Egyptians.</p>

              <p>The inspector of the kuttabs of the markaz
              also delivered a speech dealing with the new
              method of teaching in the kuttabs, and also
              recalled the Prophet’s sayings on the subject,
              pointing out that these new methods of teaching
              were the same as those enjoined by the Koran.
              He mentioned that there are now about
              sixty kuttabs in the district of Zifta at-
              tended by 3,528 scholars, of whom 105 are
              girls. He added that there was only one kut-
              tab in the whole district in 1902.</p>

              <p>Afterwards the grants-in-aid which amount-
              ed to about LE 245, were distributed and the
              meeting dispersed.</p>

              <p>(From our Correspondent).
              Santa, Wednesday.</p>

              <p>The distribution of the grants in-aid to the
              fikis and arifs of the kuttabs in this district
              took place at 11 a.m. to-day in a hall before
              the markaz, under the presidency of the Wakil
              el moudirieh of Gharbieh and two Public In-
              struction inspectors. The Wakil-el Moudirieh
              and both inspectors delivered addresses to the
              omdeh and notables on the subject of building
              kuttabs in the surrounding villages and thank-
              ed them for their generosity. Then the grants-
              in-aid were distributed to the fikis.</p></div>

              <div type= "PERSONAL AND SOCIAL">

             <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>

              <p>Lord Cromer, who is now convalescent, went
              out for a drive yesterday, and will drive out
              again today.</p>

              <p>The Dowager Countess of Donoughmore and
              Lady Nora Hutchinson have left for Assouan,
              after a prolonged stay at the Hotel d’Angle-
              terre.</p>

              <p>Lord and Lady Trevor have taken passage
              by the Orient liner Ophir, and will stay in
              Cairo at the Hotel d’Angleterre for a few days
              before going on their trip up the Nile.</p>

              <p>Sir C. Thomas and Lady Acland are expect-
              ed at Cairo in the middle of January, and have
              retained a suite of apartments at the Hotel
              d’Angleterre.</p>

              <p>Admiral Fanshawe and his secretary are
              staying at Ghezireh Palace Hotel.</p>

              <p>Mr. George Pauling, the well known S.
              African, is also staying at the Ghezireh
              Palace Hotel.</p>

              <p>Mr. A. L. Webb, C.M.G., returns to Cairo
              tonight alter an inspecting tour in Upper
              Egypt.</p>

              <p>Major Wolfgang Freiherr and Freifran
              Trensch von Buttlar-Brendenfels have returned
              to Cairo after a trip on the Nile and a visit
              to Assouan.</p>

              <p>Mrs. Thornton and Mrs. Gairdner gave an
              “at home” on Wednesday afternoon at Beit
              Arabi Pasha, Cairo. which was largely attended.
              The music and 'Xmas carols were highly
              appreciated. Both Mr. and Mrs. Gairdner are
              musical. Mrs. Gairdner is an accomplished
              violinist.</p>

              <p>Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern
              Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr. F. W.
              Lucke, Mr. A. H Loss, Mr. R. F. R. Cooke,
              Mr. and Mrs. P. Wood, Miss Wood, Mr. Wood,
              Mr. T. Wood, Mr. M. Wood, Mr. R. Wood,
              General and Mrs. Lance, Miss Billen, Mr. R
              H. du Boulay, Mr. and Mrs. H. Maës, Mr. F.
              Muriel-Wright, Comte de Failly, Mr. de St.
              Legier, Mr. and Mrs. B Hardme, Mr. Etche-
              goyeu, Mr. and Mrs. H. S. Cowper, Mr. E. P.
              Williams, Mr. and Mrs. Wildhagen, Miss M.
              Davie, Miss A. Davis, Mr. L. Stienon, Mr. G.
              Giammugnai.</p></div>

              <div type= "GHEZIREG PALACE DANCE">

                <head>GHEZIREH PALACE DANCE.</head>
              <p>Last night's dance at Ghezireh Palace Hotel
              was a most brilliant and enjoyable function.
              Over a hundred visitors and many residents,
              in addition to those staying at the hotel,
              were present, and many dinners were ordered.
              Among those dining were Col. Gordon, who
              entertained a large party, including General
              and Mrs. Bullock ; Lady Lampson, who pre-
              sided at a table of eight covers ; Major and
              Mrs. Hesse ; Mr. Curthy, who was entertain-
              ing a party of friends, including the Hon. F. G.
              Morgan, Mr. Rom, and others ; Sir Hugh
              Smiley, with a party of six ; Major Wilson,
              Mr. and Mrs. Fisher, and many others.</p>

              <p>Dancing started shortly after 10 o’clock, to
              the strains of the Tzigane Band, which played
              excellently. The floor was in good condition
              and dancing lasted till early this morning,
              when the last guests returned to town by
              motor.</p>

              <div type= "EGYPTIAN NITRATE AND PHOSPHATE SYNDICATE, LIMITED">

                <head>EGYPTIAN NITRATE AND
              PHOSPHATE SYNDICATE, LIMITED.</head>

              <p>This winding-up petition came before Mr.
              Justice Buckley on the 19th December. The
              petitioner, Mr. Henry John Monson, claimed
              to be a creditor for £1,750 and a shareholder.
              His claims, however, were contested by the
              company, and the petition was adjourned for
              the question to be fought out regarding the
              petitioner's position in another court.</p></div>

              <div type= "ZIZINIA THEATRE">

                <head>ZIZINIA THEATRE.</head>
              <p>We have received the following for insertion:</p>

              <p>L' Administration du Théâtre Zizinia informs
              Messieurs les Abonnés de la Série. A que le
              représentation du Mardi 9 Janvier 1906 set
              remise au retour du Cairo de la Compagnie
              d'Opéra.</p>

              <p>La date sera, fixée plus tardet communiquée
              par un avis spécial.</p>

              <p>L'Administration prévient Messieurs les
              Abonnés de la Série B que le Vendredi 29 Dé-
              cembre il y aura Relâche et que la representa-
              tion, pae ce fait, leur sera dûe et remise au
              Mardi 9 Janvier 1906.</p>

              <p>La direction a pris ces décisions afin de
              pouvoir, sauf cas de force majeure, attributer
              les mêmes spectacles à chaque Série et changer
              d'Opêra à chaque représentation.</p></div>

              <div type= "BAND PERFORMANCE">

                <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
              <p>By kind permission of Lieut. Colonel E.C.C
              Cox, commanding, and officers 2nd Battalion
              Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, the Band will per-
              form the following selection of music on the
              Terrace, Shepheard's Hotel on Saturday after-
              noon from 4 to 6.</p>
              <p>March-Stars and Stripes for ever-Sousa
              Overture-The Merry Monarch-Herold
              Pas de Deux-Beauty of thE Dance-Fusby
              Selection-The Belle of New York-Kerker
              Valse-Soldsten Disder Gung'l
              Song-Asthore Trotere
              American Sketch-Down South-Myddleton
              Dance de Czechs Kottane
              Regimental March- Khedivial Anthem
              God Save the King
              R. Watsch Ramsey, Bandmaster</p></div>
 </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
